Nischal Dahal

https://github.com/broisnischal | https://nischal-dahal.com.np/links +9779812745309 | info@nischal-dahal.com.np | 17 Mar, 2006 | Kathmandu, Nepal

Summary

Well-qualified developer with a focus on api & serverless architecture, web & android development, user experience, and product development, familiar with a wide range of tools and technologies, and programming knowledge, as a firm believer in transhumanism, I envision a future where technology alleviates human suffering and fosters a more harmonious world.

Experiences

AITC International

Full Stack Developer | 02/2022 - Present

- Ensured secure permission handling regarding user roles, organisation role with Role-Based Access Control.
- Integrated third party apis to enhance the functionality and improve overall user experience on the webpage, and sentry for monitoring and ensuring uptime.
- Used relational, non-relational, graph and memory database for managing and creating app.
- Enhance user experience, increased traffic by 15% developing and implementing a responsive frontend application with minimal and user friendly designs.
- Implemented animation libraries like framer-motion, pop motion and gasp for creating delightful webpages and micro interactions.
- Developed cross platform flutter application, for Visitor management system project including client app and guard app in flutter clean architecture, bloc, injectable, auto router, *implementing* web sockets, polling, real time notifications, permission management, ai detections, and more.
- Implemented system design architecture and created projects both on monolithic and micro services architecture.
- Led the development of monolithic application using tools like nx, Lerna and turborepo while delivering zero downtime development.
- Implemented Terraform for managing Kubernetes clusters and automatically provision our services, GCP, OAuth authentication, Google Secret Manager, Container Registry to store docker containers.
- Managed mobile app releases on Google play console and the App Store, incorporating CI/CD for streamlined deployment.

AITC International

Full Stack Developer Intern | 01/2022 - 02/2022

- Learned to setup PostgresDB data replication and ensure high availability of pg instances.
- Optimised website performance through efficient code refactoring and best practices.
- Implemented the search functionality like Elastic Search using Lucene Standard Algorithm, and edgegram method, creating recommendation and autocomplete system.
- Developed backend in microservices architecture, integrated rabbitmq for cross api services communication and BBF to build scalable and robust system.
- Implemented advanced vector similarity search using pgvector, enabling efficient point-in-time recovery with optimised precision, distance calculation, improving search performance and data retrieval accuracy.

VRIT Technologies

Graphic Designer & Content Creator | 09/2021 - 02/2022

- Designed visually appealing graphics, content for marketing and social media campaigns.
- Edited high-quality video content for promotional use, utilized tools like Photoshop, Illustrator, Figma, Premiere pro, Final Cut Pro, etc.

Projects work

- Developed Figma Plugin, that generates the code for tailwind configuration, arb intl, color constants and exporting assets making easier transition from design to development.
- Created "Commit Al", a tool for auto-committing git message using libraries like commander, inquirer, readline and @google/generative-ai.
- Developed https://pub.dev/packages/sandesh a flutter toast library.
- Created and maintaining https://github.com/broisnischal/prisma-fns npmjs package for seamless prisma extension integration.
- Creating AI Expense tracker application, using modern tech stack including bun, hono, Lucia auth, remix, flutter, firebase, cloudflare workers, pages, vectorize, ai, and kv.
- Golang backend in clean architecture with gin, go test, swagger, also used Jenkins for devops pipeline, docker, and IKS deployment.
- Developed myresume, a resume builder and portfolio starter kit for developers, with tools like remix, react router, tanstack guery, tanstack router, prisma, <u>fly.io</u>.
- Built an RAG Application utilizing Upstash for vector storage and integrating Llama with cloudflare AI workers for embedding management.
- Maintaining personal portfolio, publishing blogs, links, bookmarks content that I like.

Education

Bachelor in Computer Science (Undergoing)

Premier Secondary School | Baneshowr, Kathmandu | 2020 - 2022 High School (Major Science) - 3.06 CGPA

Hanumanteshwor Secondary School | Mainapokhari, Dolakha | 2018 - 2020 Secondary Education (Major Computer Science) - 3.65 CGPA

Skills

General: API Design & Development, Pipeline Management, Serverless, Database design & monitoring, Scaling API & Database, Mobile Application Development, Tools Development **Languages**: Typescript, Dart, Python, Rust, Go, C

Tools: Vim, Docker, Kubernetes, Terraform, Kafka, Playwright, Ngnix, Caddy, Cloudflare, Bun, Node, ReactJS, Flutter, Axum, DrizzleORM, Prisma

Languages

Nepali (Native), English (Professional Working), Hindi (Fluent)

Certificates

- API Design and System design on Coursera.
- Basic Data science on Udacity.
- Duolingo English Proficiency Test with score of 130-135

Achievements

- Successfully grew the Routine of Nepal Technology to over 50K followers and 10M reach, boosting community engagement and brand visibility.
- Completed 100 days of typescript-type challenges, demonstrating advanced proficiency and problem-solving skills in typescript.

Research

• Co-authored a research paper on "Machine learning & artificial intelligence: Impact and Innovations", exploring the advancement and ethical considerations in Al.

About :

https://nischal-dahal.com.np/about